Benjamin Muoka

Python Developer | Renewable Energy Engineer

Professional Summary

Analytical, motivated and hard-working Engineer with experience in the design, development, and maintenance of applications. Also, experienced in the design and installation of both on-grid and offgrid solar energy systems. Able to create efficient, scalable, and maintainable code that addresses the needs of the business and its customers. As well as perform site assessment and capable of operating equipment and hand tools. Reliable team player with a personable nature and positive communication style.

Work History

Junior Python Developer

(2022 - 2023)

Fiber, Abuja

- Python application development, testing, and maintenance.
- Working with other developers, designers, and stakeholders to satisfy project needs.
- Troubleshooting and code debugging.
- Developing and maintaining code and application documentation.
- Ensuring client feature requests are being evaluated and prioritized.
- Improve responsiveness and overall performance by developing back-end components.

Solar Business Executive

(2020 - 2022)

Abuja Graduate School, Abuja

- o Developing new solar training programs
- Coordinating and facilitating various solar workshops within and outside the institution.
- Working with the engineering team to complete various solar installations.
- Receiving and recommending solar equipment for the institution.
- Conducting various marketing activities through on-line and in-person discussions.
- Preparing various written communications, reports and documents.

Admin/Customer Relations Officer (2016 – 2017)

Institute of Management and Technology, Enugu

- Provided support to office staff, promoting excellence in office operations.
- Managed office files and records, adhering to standard procedures to prevent breaches and data misuse.
- Sorted, opened and routed incoming correspondence and deliveries.
- Scheduling appointments/meetings, organizing presentation materials and developing required databases.

Portfolio Website

https://benjaminportfolio.onrender.com/

Contact

Phone

+2348179612879

E-mail

benmuoka05@gmail.com

Education

Master of Science (M.S.) -Renewable Energy Engineering

Heriot–Watt University, United Kingdom (Oct. 2020)

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Electrical and Electronic Engineering

University of East London, Malaysia (Feb. 2016)

- Dean's List (2014/2015 Session)
- Dean's List (2013/2014 Session)

Skills

- Python, MATLAB
- Data Analysis
- Full Stack Development
- Database Management
- Bot Creation and Automation
- Git and Version Control
- ANSYS
- EnergyPlan
- Thermal modelling and analysis
- Solar design and installation
- o MS Office

Languages

English - Native

Licenses & Certifications

Python Developer (2023) *Brainnest*

Associate Member (2020) Nigerian Society of Engineers (NSE) – 54637

Projects

- Developed an application to calculate the typing speed of the user.
- Built a to-do list website where the user can save a to-do list such as a grocery list or tasks to complete.
- Wrote a python script for the tic-tac-toe game played using the terminal
- O Developed python code that converts PDF to an audiobook
- Built an image colour palette website that extracts the top ten colour from an image uploaded by a user
- o Built a bot to automate the popular google dinosaur game
- Developed a desktop app that makes typed text disappear at five seconds of no typing.
- Wrote a python script to scrap data from a website, cleaned and saved the data in a csv.
- o Built the popular breakout game.

Accomplishments

- Managed an engineering team to successfully complete the installation of a 20Kva online inverter system with 360V battery backup.
- Coordinated solar power installation and maintenance workshops across the 36 States of the Federation and the Federal Capital Territory (FCT), between November and December 2021.
- Secured Council for the Regulation of Engineering in Nigeria (COREN) accreditation to deliver SPVI, SPVIS, MGD, EA and EM programs.

Interests

Reading, Playing soccer

References

Available on request